{"name": "61C  2006-1", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1.  Two enterprising college students decide to start a business. They will make up and deliver helium balloon bouquets for special occasions. It will cost them $39.99 to buy a machine to fill the balloons with helium. They estimate that it will cost them $2.00 to buy the balloons, helium, and ribbons needed to make each balloon bouquet. Which of the following expressions could be used to model the total cost for producing b balloon bouquets?", "choices": {"A": " $2.00b + $39.99", "B": " $37.99b", "C": " $39.99b + $2.00", "D": " $41.99b", "E": " $79.98b"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.  What is the value of the expression (x \u2013 y)2 when x = 5 and y = \u20131 ?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 6", "C": " 16", "D": " 24", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  On the first day of school, Mr. Vilani gave his third-grade students 5 new words to spell. On each day of school after that, he gave the students 3 new words to spell. In the first 20 days of school, how many new words had he given the students to spell?", "choices": {"A": " 28", "B": " 62", "C": " 65", "D": " 68", "E": " 152"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  Which of the following is equivalent to (4x2)3 ?", "choices": {"A": "64x8", "B": " 64x6 ", "C": " 12x6 ", "D": " 12x5", "E": " 4x6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  Which of the following lists all the positive factors of  8 ?", "choices": {"A": " 1, 8", "B": " 2, 4", "C": " 2, 4, 6", "D": " 8, 16, 32", "E": " 1, 2, 4, 8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  Which of the following is an equivalent simplified expression for 2(4x + 7) \u2013 3(2x \u2013 4) ?", "choices": {"A": " x + 2", "B": " 2x + 2", "C": " 2x + 26", "D": " 3x + 10", "E": " 3x + 11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  To determine a student's overall test score for the semester, Ms. Lopez throws out the lowest test score and takes the average of the remaining test scores. Victor earned the following test scores in Ms. Lopez's class this semester: 62, 78, 83, 84, and 93. What overall test score did Victor earn in Ms. Lopez's class this semester?", "choices": {"A": " 67.6", "B": " 80.0", "C": " 83.0", "D": " 83.5", "E": " 84.5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8.  Uptown Cable, a cable TV provider, charges each customer $120 for installation, plus $25 per month for cable programming. Uptown's competitor, Downtown Cable, charges each customer $60 for installation, plus $35 per month for cable programming. A customer who signs up with Uptown will pay the same total amount for cable TV as a customer who signs up with Downtown if each pays for installation and cable programming for how many months?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 6", "C": " 10", "D": " 18", "E": " 30"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  In the 8-sided figure below, adjacent sides meet at right angles and the  lengths given are  in  meters. What is the perimeter of the figure, in meters?", "choices": {"A": " 40", "B": " 80", "C": " 120", "D": " 160", "E": " 400"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  The sum of the real numbers x and y is 11. Their difference is 5. What is the value of xy ?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 5", "C": " 8", "D": " 24", "E": " 55"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11.  For all x, (3x + 7)2 = ?", "choices": {"A": " 6x + 14", "B": " 6x2 + 14", "C": " 9x2 + 49", "D": " 9x2 + 21x + 49", "E": " 9x2 + 42x + 49"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  What is the slope of the line through (\u20135,2) and (6,7) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " 9", "B": " 5", "C": "-5", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. When , what is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 6", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14.  What is the length, in feet, of the hypotenuse of a right triangle with legs that are 6 feet long and 7 feet long, respectively?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 13", "D": " 21", "E": " 42"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Hexagon ABCDEF shown below was drawn on a grid with unit squares. Each vertex is at  the  intersection of 2 grid lines. What is the area of the hexagon, in square units?", "choices": {"A": " 18", "B": " 19", "C": " 20", "D": " 22", "E": " 25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. In the figure below, AD is perpendicular to BD, AC is perpendicular to BC , and AD \u224c BC . Which of the following congruences is NOT necessarily true?", "choices": {"A": "AC \u224c BD", "B": "AD \u224c AE", "C": "AE \u224c BE", "D": "\u2220DAB \u224c \u2220CBA", "E": " \u2220EAB \u224c \u2220EBA"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  Leticia went into Discount Music to price CDs. All CDs were discounted 23% off the marked price. Leticia wanted to program her calculator so she could input the marked price and the discounted price would be the output. Which of the following is an expression for the discounted price on a marked price of p dollars?", "choices": {"A": " p - 0.23p", "B": " p - 0.23", "C": " p - 23p", "D": " p - 23", "E": " 0.23p"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  In the figure below, A, D, B, and G are collinear. If \u2220CAD measures 76\u00b0, \u2220BCD measures 47\u00b0, and \u2220CBG measures 140\u00b0, what is the degree measure of \u2220ACD ?", "choices": {"A": " 12\u00b0", "B": " 14\u00b0", "C": " 17\u00b0", "D": " 36\u00b0", "E": " 43\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  Ms. Lewis plans to drive 900 miles to her vacation destination, driving an average of 50 miles per hour. How many miles per hour faster must she average, while driving, to  reduce  her  total  driving  time  by 3 hours?", "choices": {"A": " 5", "B": " 8", "C": " 10", "D": " 15", "E": " 18"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  For all positive integers x, what is the greatest common factor of the 2 numbers 216x and 180x ?", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 72", "C": " x", "D": " 12x", "E": " 36x"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. The table below shows the price of different quantities of standard-sized lemons at Joe's Fruit Stand. What is the least amount of money needed to purchase exactly 20 standard-sized lemons if the bags must be sold intact and there is no tax charged for lemons?", "choices": {"A": " $3.60", "B": " $3.90", "C": " $4.20", "D": " $4.50", "E": " $6.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  The diameter, d centimeters, of the metal poles Goodpole Manufacturing produces must satisfy the inequality | d \u2013 3 | \u2264 0.001. What is the maximum diameter, in centimeters, such a metal pole may have?", "choices": {"A": " 1.4995", "B": " 1.5005", "C": " 2.999", "D": " 3.000", "E": " 3.001"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  Which of the following is a factored form of the expression 5x2 \u2013 13x \u2013 6 ?", "choices": {"A": " (x \u2013  3)(5x + 2)", "B": " (x \u2013 2)(5x - 3)", "C": " (x \u2013 2)(5x + 3)", "D": " (x + 2)(5x - 3)", "E": " (x + 3)(5x - 2)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  A bag contains 6  red marbles, 5  yellow marbles, and  7 green marbles. How many additional red marbles must be added to the 18 marbles already in the bag so that the probability of randomly drawing a red marble is  ?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 16", "C": " 18", "D": " 24", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Which of the following trigonometric equations is valid for the side measurement x inches, diagonal measurement y inches, and angle measurement w\u00b0 in the rectangle shown below?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  The slope of the line with equation y = ax + b is greater than the slope of the line with equation y = cx + b. Which of the following statements must be true about the relationship between a and c ?", "choices": {"A": " a \u2264 c", "B": " a &lt; c", "C": " a = c", "D": " a &gt; c", "E": " a \u2265 c + 1"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Minh cuts a board in the shape of a regular hexagon  and pounds in a nail at an equal distance from each vertex, as shown in the figure below. How many rubber bands will she need in order to stretch a different rubber band across every possible pair of nails?", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 14", "C": " 12", "D": " 9", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.  There are 280 runners registered for a race, and the runners are divided into 4 age categories, as shown in  the table below.The prize committee has 60 prizes to award and wants the prizes to be awarded in proportion to the number of runners registered in each category. How many prizes should be designated for the 26\u201335 age category?", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 17", "C": " 24", "D": " 36", "E": " 40"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer questions 29-32.The youth center has installed a swimming pool on level ground. The pool is a right circular cylinder with a diameter  of 24 feet and a height of 6 feet. A diagram of the pool and   its entry ladder is shown below.29. To the nearest cubic foot, what is the volume of water that will be in the pool when it is filled with water to a depth of 5 feet?(Note:  The  volume  of  a  cylinder  is  given by \u03c0r2h,\twhere r is the radius and h is the height.)", "choices": {"A": " 942", "B": " 1,885", "C": " 2,262", "D": " 9,047", "E": " 11,310"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Use the following information to answer questions 29-32.The youth center has installed a swimming pool on level ground. The pool is a right circular cylinder with a diameter  of 24 feet and a height of 6 feet. A diagram of the pool and   its entry ladder is shown below.30. A plastic cover is made for the pool. The cover will  rest on the top of the pool and will include a wedge-shaped flap that forms a 45\u00b0 angle at the  center of the cover, as shown in the figure below. A zipper will go along 1 side of the wedge-shaped flap and around the arc. Which of the following is closest to the length, in feet, of the zipper?", "choices": {"A": " 17", "B": " 22", "C": " 24", "D": " 29", "E": " 57"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Use the following information to answer questions 29-32.The youth center has installed a swimming pool on level ground. The pool is a right circular cylinder with a diameter  of 24 feet and a height of 6 feet. A diagram of the pool and   its entry ladder is shown below.31. Two hoses are used to fill the pool. Twice as many gallons of water per minute flow through one of the hoses as through the other.  Both  hoses  had  been  on  for 12 hours and had filled the pool to the 4-foot mark when the hose with the faster flow stopped working. The hose with the slower flow then finished filling the pool to the 5-foot mark. Which of the following graphs shows the relationship between the time spent filling the pool and the height of the water in the pool?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 29-32.The youth center has installed a swimming pool on level ground. The pool is a right circular cylinder with a diameter  of 24 feet and a height of 6 feet. A diagram of the pool and   its entry ladder is shown below.32. The directions for assembling the pool state that the ladder should be placed at an angle of 75\u00b0 relative to level ground. Which of the following expressions involving tangent gives the distance, in feet, that the bottom of the ladder should be placed away from the bottom edge of the pool in order to comply with the directions?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 6 tan 75\u00b0", "E": " tan (6 \u00b7 75\u00b0)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  For a population that grows at a constant rate of r% per year, the formula  models the population t years after an initial population of Po people is counted.The population of the city of San Jose was 782,000 in 1990. Assume the population grows at a  constant rate of 5% per year. According to this formula, which of  the following is an expression for the population of San Jose in the year 2000 ?", "choices": {"A": " 782,000(6)10 ", "B": " 782,000(1.5)10", "C": " 782,000(1.05)10", "D": " (782,000 \u00d7 1.5)10", "E": " (782,000 \u00d7 1.05)10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34.  Tom's long-distance service charges $0.10 per minute from 7:00 P.M. to 7:00 A.M. on weekdays, all day on Saturdays, and all day on holidays; $0.05 per minute  all day on Sundays; and $0.25 per minute at all other times. The table below gives his long-distance calls for 1 week, including the date and day of each call, the time it was placed, and the number of minutes it lasted.What did Tom's long-distance service charge him for the calls in the table?", "choices": {"A": " $7.30", "B": " $7.60", "C": " $7.95", "D": " $8.80", "E": " $9.90"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  The parallel sides of the isosceles trapezoid shown below are 10 feet long and 16 feet long, respectively. What is the distance, in feet, between these 2 sides?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 4", "C": " 5", "D": " 10", "E": " 16"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36.  The inequality 3(x + 2) &gt; 4(x \u2013 3) is equivalent to which of the following inequalities?", "choices": {"A": " x &lt; -6", "B": " x &lt; 5", "C": " x &lt; 9", "D": " x &lt; 14", "E": " x &lt; 18"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37.  In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the midpoint of AB is (4,\u20133) and A is located at (1,\u20135). If (x,y) are the coordinates of B, what is the value of x + y ?", "choices": {"A": " 19", "B": " 8", "C": " 6", "D": " -1.5", "E": " -3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38.  For all x in the domain of the function  , this function is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In the figure below, line l is parallel to line m. Transversals t and u intersect at point A on l and intersect m   at points C and B, respectively. Point X is on m, the measure of \u2220ACX is 130\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220BAC is 80\u00b0. How many of the angles formed by rays of l, m, t, and u have measure 50\u00b0 ?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 6", "C": " 8", "D": " 10", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40.  Tickets for the Senior Talent Show at George Washington Carver High School are $3 for adults and $2 for students. To cover expenses, a total of $600 must be collected from ticket sales for the show. One of the following graphs in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, where x is the number of adult tickets sold and y is the number of student tickets sold, represents all the possible combinations of ticket sales that cover at least $600 in expenses. Which graph is it?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. What is the median of the following 7 scores?        42, 67, 33, 79, 33, 89, 21", "choices": {"A": " 42", "B": " 52", "C": " 54.5", "D": " 56", "E": " 79"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42.  What are the real solutions to the equation |x|2 + 2|x| -3 = 0?", "choices": {"A": " \u00b11", "B": " \u00b13", "C": " 1 and 3", "D": " -1 and -3", "E": " \u00b11 and \u00b13"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  The point (2,5) is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Which of the following is another point on  the  line through the  point (2,5) with a slope of  \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " A(-1,3)", "B": "B(0,8)", "C": " C(4,2)", "D": " D(5,3)", "E": " E(5,7)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  For the triangles in the figure below, which of the following ratios of side lengths is equivalent to  the  ratio  of the perimeter of \u25b3ABC to the perimeter of \u25b3DAB ?", "choices": {"A": " AB:AD", "B": " AB:BD", "C": " AD:BD", "D": " BC:AD", "E": " BC:BD"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45.  In the figure below, 2 nonadjacent sides of a regular pentagon (5 congruent sides and 5 congruent interior angles) are  extended until they meet at  point X. What is the measure of \u2220X ?", "choices": {"A": " 18\u00b0", "B": " 30\u00b0", "C": " 36\u00b0", "D": " 45\u00b0", "E": " 72\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  The edges of a cube are each 3 inches long. What is the surface area, in square inches, of this cube?", "choices": {"A": " 9", "B": " 18", "C": " 27", "D": " 36", "E": " 54"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  A number is increased by 25% and the resulting number is then decreased by 20%. The final number is what percent of the original number?", "choices": {"A": " 90%", "B": " 95%", "C": " 100%", "D": " 105%", "E": " 120%"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  Two numbers are reciprocals if  their product is  equal  to 1. If x and y are reciprocals and x &gt; 1, then y must    be:", "choices": {"A": " less than \u20131.", "B": " between 0 and \u20131.", "C": " equal to 0.", "D": " between 0 and 1.", "E": " greater than 1."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49.  The number line graph below is the graph of which of the following inequalities?", "choices": {"A": " -1 \u2264 x and 3 \u2264  x", "B": " \u20131 \u2264 x and 3 \u2265  x", "C": " \u20131 \u2264 x or 3 \u2264  x", "D": " \u20131 \u2265 x or 3 \u2264  x", "E": " \u20131 \u2265 x or 3 \u2265  x"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50.  All of the following graphs have equal scales on the axes. One of the graphs shows only points for which the y-coordinate is 1 less than the square of the x-coordinate. Which one?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51.  In teaching a lesson on the concept of thirds, Ms. Chu uses a divide-and-set-aside procedure. She starts with a certain number of colored disks, divides them into 3 equal groups, and sets 1 group aside to illustrate . She repeats the procedure by taking the disks she had NOT set aside, dividing them into 3 equal groups, and setting 1 of these groups aside. If Ms. Chu wants to be able to complete the divide-and-set-aside procedure at least 4 times (without breaking any of the disks into pieces), which of the following is the minimum number of colored disks she can start with?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 15", "C": " 27", "D": " 54", "E": " 81"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  Which of the following is true for all consecutive integers m and n such that m &lt; n ?", "choices": {"A": " m is odd", "B": " n is odd", "C": " n-m is even", "D": "n2 - m2 is odd", "E": "m2 + n2 is even"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A function P is defined as follows:for x &gt; 0, P(x) =   x5 + x4 \u2013 36x \u2013 36for x &lt; 0, P(x) = \u2013x5 + x4 + 36x \u2013 36 What is the value of P(\u20131) ?", "choices": {"A": " -70", "B": " -36", "C": " 0", "D": " 36", "E": " 70"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  For a project in Home Economics class, Kirk is making a tablecloth for a circular table 3 feet in diameter. The  finished tablecloth needs to  hang down   5 inches over the edge of the table all the way around. To finish the edge of the tablecloth, Kirk will fold under and sew down 1 inch of the  material all  around the edge. Kirk is going to use a single piece of rectangular fabric that is 60 inches wide. What is the shortest length of fabric, in inches, Kirk could use to make the tablecloth without putting any separate pieces of fabric together?", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 24", "C": " 30", "D": " 42", "E": " 48"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The equations of the 2  graphs  shown  below  are  y1(t) = a1 sin(b1t) and y2(t) = a2 cos(b2t), where the constants b1 and b2 are both positive real numbers.Which of the following statements is true of the constants a1 and a2 ?", "choices": {"A": "0 &lt; a1 &lt; a2 ", "B": " 0 &lt;  a2 &lt; a1", "C": " a1 &lt; 0 &lt; a2 ", "D": " a1 &lt; a2 &lt; 0", "E": " a2 &lt; a1 &lt; 0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56.  For x such that  , the expression  is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 1", "C": " 2", "D": " -tan x", "E": " sin 2x"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  Consider the functions  and . In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane,  passes through (4,6). What is the value of b ?", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " -8", "C": " -25", "D": " -26", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  The triangle, \u25b3XYZ, that is shown below has side lengths of x, y, and z inches and is not a right triangle. Let X\u2032 be the image of X when the triangle is reflected across YZ . Which of the following is an expression for the perimeter, in inches, of quadrilateral X\u2032YXZ ?", "choices": {"A": " 2(y + z) + x", "B": " 2(x + y + z)", "C": " 2(x + y)", "D": " 2(x + z)", "E": " 2(y + z)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  A  function  f   is   an   odd  function  if   and  only  if  f(\u2013x) = \u2013f(x) for every value of x in the domain of f. One of the functions graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below is an odd function. Which one?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  What is the real value of x in the equation log224 \u2013 log23 = log5 x ?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 21", "C": " 72", "D": " 125", "E": " 243"}, "correct": "D"}]}